







Summary

Jump to Section

7 years of experience in Web applications development and maintenance using Java, J2EE, Spring, Hibernate and related technologies. Within this am having 2 years of onsite experience with notable success. 2.5 years of working experience in IBMODM. Having valid H1B VISA till April 2021.

Good experience in Travel and Hospitality Domain.

Capable senior team player who works well with people at all levels.

Experience in writing the technical and functional design documents

Experience in design, development and implementation of Model- View - Controller using Spring M/C and Spring Boot. Good working experience with Web Services.

Hands on experience in Servlets, JDBC, Log4j, JNDI and SQL.

Hands on experience using several J2EE design patterns like Singleton and Dependency Injection.

Work Experience

Cognizant Technology Solutions as Senior Projects Associate -Java/J2EE Jun 2011 to Till Date

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Major Project Synopsis:

Project: WWO App Dev Project (Jan 2020 to till now)

Client: Wyndham Vacation Ownership

Location: Kolkata, India

Description: WWO is considered within the timeshare industry as the global leader in vacation Ownership. The objectives of this project are to develop/enhance different J2EE applications and ODMMgration from v8.5.1 to v8.10.2.

Responsibilities:

Utilize Agile process to streamline development process with iterative development.

Understand the business requirements document then analyse and write the Technical Design document.

Develop new features in Java and Versata framework called IRIS.

Develop ODM integration layer compatible with tomcat server.

Migrate all rule projects from ODM v8.5.1 to v8.10.2.

Deploy all rule projects in RES and test.

Work with calling application team for testing from apps and fix any issue.

Run OTA tool to find out deprecated features

Work with QA team and fix defects after deployment.

Technologies Used: JDK 1.8, J2EE, IBM ODM, Versata, Log4J, Spring M/C, Web Services, Maven, TFS, Websphere, Tomcat.

Project: WVO App Support (Jan 2017 to Dec 2019) Client: Wyndham Vacation Ownership Location: Kolkata. India and Florida. USA



Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Description: WWO is considered within the timeshare industry as the global leader in vacation Ownership. The objective of the project is to maintain/enhance different applications across different technology towers. Applications supported in this portfolio include Digital Service Solutions, CSS, RCC, FOCUS, and PGI. Integral to the project is the app support run team, which is responsible for maintaining, troubleshooting, and providing access to different applications, as well as coordinating installation of upgrades, evaluating and installing new software as and when required.

Responsibilities:

Taking the full ownership of supporting multiple java-based application, lead the team to solve production issues and join high priority call with client.

Take the ownership of validating and implementing all changes that takes place for all this above-mentioned application.

Technologies Used: J2EE, Spring M/C, Versata, Web Services, Maven, TFS, Websphere, Tomcat.

Project: Project IRON (June 2016 to Dec 2016)

Client: WEX

Location: Kolkata, India

Description: WEX Virtual Travel Payment Solutions (Iron) help simplify payments to suppliers, such as hotels, car rental agencies, tour operators, and destination service providers. WEX IRON is divided into three-layer UX (front layer), OSB (Mddle Layer) and backend (BL) layer. Front layer is developed on Spring M/C, HTML 5 and angular. M/C layer calls the middle layer (OSB) using SOAP client and again OSB consumes the business layer by calling their endpoint soap web services.

Responsibilities:

Utilize Agile process to streamline development process with iterative development

Understand the business requirements document then analyse and write the Technical Design document.

Work with the business analysts to give the right product on time.

Developed front layer using Spring M/C and Angular-JS. Spring M/C consume the Middleware using SOAP Web services which call backend Business layer.

Developed Business layer using JAXWS, Hibernate and Spring Transaction for business transaction.

Developed web services endpoint (using SOAP based) and share the wsdl and xsd to OSB (Mddleware).

Developed the Rest Web services.

Responsible for integration testing and release to QA

Suggestions for database tables design and developed queries needed for this application.

Technologies Used: JDK 1.8, J2EE, Log4J, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Restful Web Services, XML, Maven, SVN, WebLogic, Tomcat, HTML 5 and Angular-JS.

Project: Application Support (Oct 2011 - May 2016) Client: Wyndham RCI Location: Kolkata, India

Description: This project is to provide level 3 Production support, maintenance and enhancement to various applications of WER across various technology platforms.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science and Engineering) from West Bengal University of Technology (WBUT) in 2011

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
JAVA, J2EE	
Hibernate, Spring MVC	
spring boot	
Oracle	
Windows 7 Professional, Windows 10	
WebSphere, Tomcat	
Servlets, Java, JDBC	
SVN, TFS	
JDBC	
Eclipse, SQL Developer	
Log4j, AppD, Splunk, JIRA, Postman	

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
D				

Bengali

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.